

RICHARD DAVIS

League City, TX 77573 | RealRichardD28@gmail.com

Summary

Proficient at explaining complicated technical concepts to users of varying degrees of technical understanding. Knowledgeable in an assortment of operating systems, applications and hardware. Motivated computer professional with more than five years of personal experience in computer installation, repair and maintenance. Dynamic computer technician experienced in various hardware, software, networking and operating systems maintenance and repair. Actively certified in CompTIA A+ & Network+ with Associates in Computer Science. Customer service-oriented, committed to understanding and resolving problems for clients quickly and accurately to reduce downtime and increase productivity.

Highlights

Organized
Customer service-focused
Knowledge of Microsoft Office applications
Reliable and dependable
Highly motivated/driven

System checks and troubleshooting
Computer diagnostics and repair
More than 5 years personal experience working with computers
Knowledge of Windows XP, 7, 8 & 10

Fast learner for on-the-job skills/knowledge

Accomplishments

- Recipient of the National Technical Honors Society Award in 2006.
- Treasurer of the Biology Club in 2007.
- Set up LLC, co-owned and managed hobby game store from 2012-2014.
- Awarded "Top Rated Seller" with 100% positive feedback on eBay from 2012-2014.
- Recipient of the Outstanding Customer Approval Award in 2014.
- Multiple recognitions by store managers for excellent customer service.
- Granted department "Team Lead" oversight for customer price adjustments by manager after only two months.
- Awarded multiple Cornerstone badges in first 12 months of employment at San Jacinto College IT

Experience

Technical Support/Help Desk Analyst I

10/21/2019 to Present

San Jacinto College: Central Campus

Pasadena, TX

Job Scope

- Be able to quickly identify end-user problems and administer solutions both on-site and remotely.
- Be able to communicate technical concepts to non-technical users to assist in the resolution of issues.
- Setup and deployed dozens of laptops/desktops, both client and lab.
- Basic knowledge of Azure Services, AD, SCCM, CMD, CMC, Print Management, RDP, Reg-Editor and more.

Xfinity Sales Professional/ Residential

06/22/2015 to 01/13/2017

Comcast/NBC/Universal Houston, TX

Job Scope

- Understand pricing and product knowledge
- Be able to communicate basic technical functions of products and services to end-user.
- Be able to identify and qualify end user's home for services. (i.e. if customer needs outlets, home security takeover, etc.)
- Go door to door to demonstrate and sell Xfinity products and services.
- Assisted sold and existing end users with basic troubleshooting or escalation of their needs.

- Setup the business, ran and managed store sales, customer service relations, vendor relations, company taxes, company website and hired/trained new employees.
- Maximized company revenue from customer product surveys, researching product reviews and taking advantage of bulk order deals from vendors based on the information gathered.
- Compiled and synthesized relevant business data such as financials and performance.
- Drafted business plans, budgets, quarterly and semi-annual business reviews.

Certifications

CompTIA Certifications: Candidate ID: COMP001021182464

CompTIA A+ certified: Certification Date: June 1, 2017 Exp: February 11, 2022 CompTIA Network+ certified: Certification Date: February 11, 2019 Exp: February 11, 2022 Certification Date: February 11, 2019 Exp: February 11, 2022 Exp: February 11, 2022

Currently studying Security+ to earn a certification.

Udemy

Mike Meyers/Total Seminars N10-006 Network+ Certification Training: Certificate of Completion:

Certificate no: UC-OGQCXV71

Education

Transfer Out for Continuing Study: Major/Minor: Biology/Chemistry

Stephen F. Austin State University

Graduation Date: N/A

Nacogdoches, TX, United States

• Member of the Pre-Health Professions Club, SFA Big Jacks, Biology Club as well as Officer of Treasury of the Biology Club.

Associates of Science: Major Area of Study: Computer Science

San Jacinto College

Graduation Date: December 14th, 2018

Houston, TX, United States

Bachelor's of Computer Science:
Major Area of Focus: Databases & Website Development
with Minor Area of Focus on Cyber Security
University of Houston Clear Lake

Houston, TX, United States

Expected Graduation Date: December 18th, 2022

Skills

- Moderate language skills for Spanish and Malay
- Fast learning curve for new information and on the job skills
- Understanding of people's needs and concerns as to explain and sell them the most appropriate products and/or services
- People skills: enthusiastic people person, advanced problem-solving, great organizational skills
- Moderate understanding of Oracle
- Moderate video editing/YouTube knowledge
- Moderate understanding of HTTP and CSS

Additional Information

Has traveled to Singapore, Malaysia, U.K., Russia and Doha. As well, has in depth knowledge and experience with multicultural environments and peoples.

Interests & Activities

I enjoy learning how to code in my free time. I have recently taken an interest in Cyber Security and FinTech and am currently working on programs for Cyber Security Analyst, SQL, Kali Linux and CompTlA Security+. I have dabbled in almost all major programming languages including, but not limited to: python, SQL, HTML, CSS, Java, Java Script, Ruby, C, C#, C++, Swift, PHP, Kotlin, Git and R.

Testimonials

My former Professor of Chemistry: Jiaxing Chen

Dear Scholarship committee,

It is my great pleasure to write in supporting Richard Davis for his STEM scholarship application. He was one of my A students in the General Chemistry I class of summer 2018. Throughout the period of the course, I found Richard is a hardworking, object oriented and highly reliable person. He completed all assigned homework and was one of few students who maintained steady scores in all exams. Again, I would like to express my strong support for Richard Davis application of STEM scholarship. Please don't hesitate to let me know if you have any question or concern regarding his capability.

Sincerely,

Jiaxing Chen Professor of Chemistry San Jacinto College Jiaxing.Chen@sjcd.edu







LinkedIn Profile: www.linkedin.com/in/richard-e-davis-jr: Blog/Website: https://davisre28.github.io/RealRichard D/